JESS YOUNG

⊠ jess@soijen.com

SUMMARY

Expertise in business operations. I work with small businesses and start-ups, focusing on process optimization and data flow. I am a scientist by training and like to dissect business problems with an analytical eye.

I care about living my life with minimal negative impact to the environment and prioritize collaborating with firms committed to sustainability.

As a professional with international experience, I am multilingual and a clear communicator to both technical and nontechnical audiences. I have lived and worked in the US, Canada and Chile.

LANGUAGES

English	****
Spanish	***
Japanese	**
French	*

KNOWLEDGE

TOOLS

HTML/CSS	****
Salesforce	****
Jekyll	****
Quickbase	****
Git/Github	***
Javascript	**

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sóijen

Co-founder: January 2017 - Present

Soijen.com is a website that connects outdoor adventurers to off-the-beaten-path spots in Patagonia. We create content such as informational articles, photos and videos to highlight less-travelled destinations in Chilean Patagonia, while partnering with local agencies to increase their visibility and online presence.

Bright Power, Inc. New York, USA

Operations Associate: January 2017 - Present

Engineering Operations Administrator: May 2015 – December 2016

Bright Power is an engineering consulting firm that helps buildings save energy. My primary role is to build internal tools to help our employees work more cohesively and efficiently.

- Structuring and building the company's central repository of information in a Salesforce database. Focus on the user experience and customizations through Visualforce and Apex code.
- Developing automation tools and integrations using Salesforce, Google Scripts, AutoHotKey and Quickbase to minimize manual tasks across company.
- Optimizing team workflow while implementing a new project management system to track energy audits across over 400 buildings across the US.

Zomato Chile, SpA. Santiago, Chile

Operations Manager: August 2014 – March 2015 Content Associate: April 2014 – August 2014

Zomato is a website and app that helps users discover new restaurants. In Santiago, Chile we built a database of 8500+ restaurants from the ground up. As Operations Manager for this fast growing start-up, I focused on growing our team and developing standardized processes.

- Heading full cycle recruitment (sales, marketing, analysts) across all verticals, from entry level to senior positions. Sourcing candidates, screening, conducting 300+ interviews, training and integration of new talent. 10 new hires.
- Implementing new expense reporting system, day-to-day bookkeeping, and working with international finance team to guarantee accountability and cost-reduction.
- Developing an HR system to ensure compliance with Chilean law including safety trainings and protocols.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University Evanston, USA

Postgraduate Researcher / Teaching Assistant: 2012 – 2013

Post-graduate studies and research in physical chemistry. The focus of my research was understanding the reactions of organic aerosol particles in the atmosphere, and their consequences in climate change. In addition I was a teaching assistant in an Organic Chemistry laboratory course and taught and mentored undergraduate students pursuing career in sciences.

McGill University Montreal, Canada

B.Sc. in Chemistry, First Class Honors: 2007 – 2011

GPA: 3.64/4.00